class QuestionModel{
  final String question;
  final List<String> options;
  final correctAnswerIndex;
  final String Solution;

  const QuestionModel({
    required this.question,
    required this.options,
    required this.correctAnswerIndex,
    required this.Solution,
  });
}


List<QuestionModel> questions = [
  QuestionModel(
      question: "1. Which part of an internal combustion engine is responsible for converting reciprocating motion into rotary motion?",
      options: [
        "A. Crankshaft",
        "B. Camshaft",
        "C. Piston",
        "D. Cylinder head"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution: "The correct answer is A. Crankshaft. The crankshaft is responsible for converting the reciprocating motion of the pistons into rotary motion, which is used to drive the vehicle's wheels."
  ),

  QuestionModel(
      question: "2. What type of transmission is most commonly found in modern passenger vehicles?",
      options: [
        "A. Manual transmission",
        "B. Automatic transmission",
        "C. Continuously variable transmission (CVT)",
        "D. Semi-automatic transmission"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: "The correct answer is B. Automatic transmission. Automatic transmissions are the most common type of transmission in modern passenger vehicles because they are easier to use and offer a smoother driving experience."
  ),

  QuestionModel(
      question: "3. What is the purpose of an automotive differential?",
      options: [
        "A. To steer the vehicle",
        "B. To transfer power to the wheels",
        "C. To control the engine's RPM",
        "D. To adjust the suspension"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: "The correct answer is B. To transfer power to the wheels. The differential is responsible for distributing power from the engine to the wheels while allowing them to rotate at different speeds, especially during turns."
  ),

  QuestionModel(
      question: "4. Which of the following is an example of a hybrid electric vehicle (HEV)?",
      options: [
        "A. Tesla Model S",
        "B. Toyota Prius",
        "C. Ford F-150",
        "D. BMW M3"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: "The correct answer is B. Toyota Prius. The Toyota Prius is an example of a hybrid electric vehicle (HEV) that combines a gasoline engine with an electric motor for improved fuel efficiency."
  ),

  QuestionModel(
      question: "5. What component in a car's suspension system is responsible for absorbing shocks and vibrations?",
      options: [
        "A. Brake caliper",
        "B. Shock absorber",
        "C. Tie rod",
        "D. Steering wheel"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: "The correct answer is B. Shock absorber. The shock absorber (or damper) is designed to absorb and dampen the shocks and vibrations generated by the road, providing a smoother and more comfortable ride."
  ),

  QuestionModel(
      question: "6. In an automotive engine, what does the term 'redline' refer to?",
      options: [
        "A. The color of the engine coolant",
        "B. The highest engine speed at which it can safely operate",
        "C. The brand of engine oil used",
        "D. The engine's serial number"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: "The correct answer is B. The highest engine speed at which it can safely operate. The redline is the maximum RPM (revolutions per minute) at which the engine can safely operate without causing damage."
  ),

  QuestionModel(
      question: "7. Which type of braking system uses hydraulic pressure to apply the brakes?",
      options: [
        "A. Mechanical brakes",
        "B. Drum brakes",
        "C. Disc brakes",
        "D. Hydraulic brakes"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution: "The correct answer is D. Hydraulic brakes. Hydraulic brakes use hydraulic pressure to transmit force from the brake pedal to the brake calipers or drums, resulting in effective braking."
  ),

  QuestionModel(
      question: "8. What does ABS stand for in the context of automotive safety?",
      options: [
        "A. Advanced Braking System",
        "B. Anti-Lock Braking System",
        "C. Automatic Braking System",
        "D. Active Brake System"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: "The correct answer is B. Anti-Lock Braking System. ABS is an abbreviation for Anti-Lock Braking System, which prevents wheel lockup during hard braking, improving control and safety."
  ),

  QuestionModel(
      question: "9. What is the primary function of an automotive radiator?",
      options: [
        "A. To cool the engine oil",
        "B. To filter impurities from the fuel",
        "C. To cool the engine by dissipating heat",
        "D. To regulate the air-fuel mixture"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: "The correct answer is C. To cool the engine by dissipating heat. Radiators are designed to cool the engine by dissipating heat generated during the combustion process, helping to maintain the engine's temperature within the optimal range."
  ),

  QuestionModel(
      question: "10. What is the purpose of a turbocharger in an automotive engine?",
      options: [
        "A. To increase fuel efficiency",
        "B. To reduce emissions",
        "C. To provide extra engine power",
        "D. To improve engine longevity"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: "The correct answer is C. To provide extra engine power. A turbocharger is used to force more air into the engine, which results in increased power output without the need for a larger engine."
  ),

  QuestionModel(
      question: "11. Which part of a car's exhaust system is responsible for reducing harmful emissions?",
      options: [
        "A. Muffler",
        "B. Catalytic converter",
        "C. Tailpipe",
        "D. Exhaust manifold"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: "The correct answer is B. Catalytic converter. The catalytic converter is designed to reduce harmful emissions by converting them into less harmful substances before they are released into the atmosphere."
  ),

  QuestionModel(
      question: "12. What is the purpose of the OBD-II (On-Board Diagnostics) system in modern vehicles?",
      options: [
        "A. To play music in the car",
        "B. To monitor engine performance",
        "C. To control the air conditioning",
        "D. To operate the navigation system"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: "The correct answer is B. To monitor engine performance. OBD-II is used to monitor and diagnose the performance of the vehicle's engine and emissions control systems, helping with maintenance and emissions compliance."
  ),

  QuestionModel(
      question: "13. Which type of fuel is commonly used in diesel engines?",
      options: [
        "A. Gasoline",
        "B. Propane",
        "C. Diesel fuel",
        "D. Ethanol"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: "The correct answer is C. Diesel fuel. Diesel engines typically use diesel fuel, which is a specific type of fuel designed for compression-ignition engines."
  ),

  QuestionModel(
      question: "14. What does the acronym CVT stand for in automotive transmission technology?",
      options: [
        "A. Constant Velocity Transmission",
        "B. Continuously Variable Transmission",
        "C. Central Valve Timing",
        "D. Controlled Viscosity Transfer"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: "The correct answer is B. Continuously Variable Transmission. CVT stands for Continuously Variable Transmission, which offers a continuous range of gear ratios for improved efficiency and performance."
  ),

  QuestionModel(
      question: "15. Which automotive safety feature is designed to inflate rapidly in the event of a collision to protect occupants?",
      options: [
        "A. Air conditioning system",
        "B. Air suspension",
        "C. Airbag",
        "D. Anti-theft system"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: "The correct answer is C. Airbag. Airbags are designed to inflate rapidly upon collision impact, providing a cushion to protect vehicle occupants from injury."
  ),

  QuestionModel(
      question: "16. What does AWD stand for in the context of vehicle drivetrains?",
      options: [
        "A. Advanced Wheel Drive",
        "B. All Weather Drive",
        "C. Automatic Wheel Drive",
        "D. All-Wheel Drive"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution: "The correct answer is D. All-Wheel Drive. AWD stands for All-Wheel Drive, which provides power to all four wheels simultaneously for improved traction and stability, especially in adverse road conditions."
  ),

  QuestionModel(
      question: "17. What is the purpose of the transmission fluid in an automatic transmission?",
      options: [
        "A. To lubricate the engine",
        "B. To cool the transmission",
        "C. To power the steering system",
        "D. To engage the brakes"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: "The correct answer is B. To cool the transmission. Transmission fluid in an automatic transmission serves to cool and lubricate the transmission components, ensuring smooth operation and preventing overheating."
  ),

  QuestionModel(
      question: "18. What is the term for the process of converting chemical energy in fuel into mechanical energy in an engine?",
      options: [
        "A. Combustion",
        "B. Compression",
        "C. Exhaustion",
        "D. Ignition"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution: "The correct answer is A. Combustion. Combustion is the process in which chemical energy in fuel is converted into mechanical energy through the controlled burning of the fuel in the engine's cylinders."
  ),

  QuestionModel(
      question: "19. What is the role of the power steering system in a vehicle?",
      options: [
        "A. To increase fuel efficiency",
        "B. To reduce engine noise",
        "C. To make steering easier for the driver",
        "D. To control the vehicle's speed"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: "The correct answer is C. To make steering easier for the driver. The power steering system assists the driver in turning the wheels, making it easier to steer the vehicle, especially at low speeds or when parking."
  ),

  QuestionModel(
      question: "20. In an electric vehicle (EV), what type of battery is commonly used for energy storage?",
      options: [
        "A. Alkaline battery",
        "B. Lead-acid battery",
        "C. Lithium-ion battery",
        "D. Nickel-cadmium battery"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: "The correct answer is C. Lithium-ion battery. Lithium-ion batteries are commonly used in electric vehicles (EVs) for energy storage due to their high energy density, lightweight, and long cycle life."
  )

];